Hedda Gabler is a drama film directed by Matthew John.
Hedda, beautiful daughter of the late General Gabler, returns from her honeymoon with
scholar husband Jorgen to confront the boredom and banality of married life.
Although she has little more than amused contempt for her husband, she is pregnant by him and is revolted by
the thought of carrying his child and the changes that motherhood will impose upon her future.
When the re-appearance of an old flame of hers threatens both Jorgen's career prospects and her own amour propre,
Hedda contrives to bring about Lovborg's destruction but, in the process, also brings about her own.
Hedda Gabler, played by Rita Ramnani.
Ejlert Løvborg, played by Francisco Ortiz.
Hedda Gabler is a film based on the 1891 Victorian period play Hedda
Gabler, written by Norwegian playwright Henrik Ibsen.
One of many adaptations of this play, the film Hedda Gabler was
produced, adapted, and directed by Matthew John.
Hedda Gabler is an example of realism in nineteenth-century playwriting, and
is one of the world's best known and most performed dramas.
The film was shot at Maunsel House.
The movie premiered at the Vika Cinema, Oslo on 8 September
2016 to open the Ibsen International Festivalen.
A press launch at the Henrik Ibsen Museum on 9 September 2016.
the event was sponsored by H+M and Radisson Blu.
Matthew John attended the red carpet with Swedish
supermodel Marcus Schenkenberg.
The title role is played by Rita Ramnani.
The film is also part of the Worcester University PR and Journalism programme.
The film had its UK premiere at the university, followed by
talks from the cast, costume designer and director.
The tone is emotional.